Hoi Man Yuen

Nationality: British

Contact Details: 07732 290428 | hoiman.k.yuen@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://hoimankyuen.github.io

Address: London SE13

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I am a Unity developer and programmer with over 4 years of experience designing and developing video games and interactive edutainment software using C# and Unity3D. From system and game design, graphics, development, and UI/UX to testing, my training in Computer Science, multidisciplinary knowledge and problem-solving skills enable me to take on most tasks independently or as part of a team. Still, I am eager to learn and improve on my expertise, and I aim to further progress into the video game industry.

WORK EXPERIENCE

R&D Engineer / Software Developer at Hactis Ltd., Hong Kong

08/2019 - 03/2023

- Initiated, researched, designed, led and developed a general-purpose multiplayer VR content builder using Unity3D and C#
- Developed various VR gamified interactive applications using Unity3D and C#
- Developed multiple UI and visual enhancements for existing and new VR solutions by creating procedurally generated graphics and shaders
- Increase development efficiency by developing abstraction tools and reusable plugins

Summer Internship at Versitech Ltd., Hong Kong

06/2018 - 08/2018

- Developed an AR FPS minigame and a VR matching game for exhibition booths using Unity3D and C#
 - Provided multiple game design proposals according to requirements
 - Performed research and provided solutions to account for resource constraints
 - Implemented game designs into completed products
 - Conduct tests to ensure product quality and user experience

Game Programmer at Uniques Digital Game Ltd., Hong Kong

09/2014 - 07/2015

- Developed new mechanics for a mobile game using Unity3D and C# (Naval Front-line)
 - Implemented new input system and gameplay elements
 - Designed and implemented new gameplay content and levels
 - Conducted tests and maintenance on existing game systems

Game Developer (Part-time) at Memoriki Ltd., Hong Kong

04/2014 - 07/2014

- Developed new mobile games using Unity3D and C#
 - Developed related utility GUI programs using C#
 - Provided designs used in game development

OTHER PROJECTS

- Work-in-progress game prototype at https://github.com/hoimankyuen/DicingHeros
 - A turn-based strategy game with physics about dice
- Experimental game prototype at https://github.com/hoimankyuen/PlaneTactics
 - A turn-based gridless strategy game about plane battles
- University game project showcase at https://innowings.engg.hku.hk/club-grenade
 - A multiplayer lite action game about defeating enemies with grenades

LANGUAGE AND TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Language: C#, C++, HLSL
Programming IDE: Visual Studio
Operating System: Microsoft Windows

Version Control System: GIT

Software & Tools: Unity3D, Adobe Photoshop, Blender

Written & Spoken Languages: English, Chinese (written), Cantonese (spoken), Japanese

EDUCATION

The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong

2015 - 2019

Bachelor of Engineering, Major in Computer Science

School of Continuing and Professional Studies, CUHK, *Hong Kong* Higher Diploma Programme in Computer Game Development

2012 - 2014